Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Jack Cronin papers, 1964-1996 and undated RL.11603
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence and Related Materials, 1975-1990 and undated; 3
  - Istanbul--David Campbell-Harris report on visit sept 1987 (Box 32)
  - Istanbul--Financial, 1985-1988 (Box 32)
  - Istanbul--Gerhard Blank's notes on visit to Turkey, 1985 (Box 32)
  - Istanbul--Manajans, 1984-1985 (Box 32)
  - Istanbul--Report on Turkey, 1986 (Box 32)
  - Istanbul--Turkey office acquisition notes (English and Turkish), 1980-1986; 7 folders (Box 32)
  - Jack Peters, 1986-1987 (Box 32)
  - JWT Group--An organizational study for JWT Company Germany, 1986 (Box 32)
  - JWT in the Middle East: A proposal from the Al Futtaim Group of Dubai (Geoffrey Dempsey), 1979 (Box 32)
  - Lansdowne Euro, 1979-1986 (Box 32)
  - Lisbon, 1984-1986; 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Lisbon--1985-1987 marketing plan (Box 33)
  - Lisbon--An outsider's view of its present and future, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Lisbon--Financial, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Lisbon--Report three suggestions on how to solve our problem 1985-1987, 1984 (Box 33)
  - London, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Madrid, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Madrid--Financial, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Manchester, 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Manchester--ASDA superstores, 1985 (Box 33)
  - Manchester--Financial, 1984 (Box 33)
  - Media, 1984 (Box 34)
  - Media clippings, 1987 (Box 34)
  - Media research replies, 1982 (Box 34)
  - Media working party, 1982-1983; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Media working party presentation (German and English), undated (Box 34)
  - Memos to and from Cronin, 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Michael Cooper Evans, 1983-1985; 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Middle East trip report (Michael Brown), 1980 (Box 34)
  - Milan, 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Milan--Annual assessment, 1985 (Box 35)
  - Milan--Financial, 1984 (Box 35)
  - Milan--Some background information and general thoughts about our new operation in the Middle East, 1985 (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1984-1985; 3 folders (Box 35)
  - Montreal, 1982-1984 (Box 35)
  - MRB (Market Research Bureau), 1979-1986 (Box 35)
  - MRBI, 1981-1984; 4 folders (Box 36)
  - MRBI--Financial, 1983 (Box 36)
  - MRBI--JWT and market research, undated (Box 36)
  - MRBI--Opportunities for JWT in market research, 1983 (Box 36)
  - Multinational Client Services, 1985 (Box 36)
  - New media development (Roy Langridge), 1982 (Box 36)
  - New York, 1983-1986; 4 folders (Box 37)
  - Paris, 1981-1985; 3 folders (Box 37)
  - Paris--Financial, 1984-1985 (Box 37)
  - Ray Sargent, 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Retail power seminar, 1984-1985 (Box 38)
  - Retail power seminar--Crisis in branding, 1978 (Box 38)
  - Seminars, 1983; 2 folders (Box 38)
  - Stockholm, 1984 (Box 38)
  - Stockholm--Financial, 1984 (Box 38)
  - Survey of agency remuneration bySociety of British Advertisers, 1981 (Box 38)
  - Sydney, 1983-1986 (Box 38)
  - Television today and tomorrow (correspondence concerning the book by Toby Syfret), 1983 (Box 38)
  - Thompson Associates Middle East, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
  - Thompson Associates Middle East, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Toronto, 1982-1986 (Box 39)
  - Toronto--Moosehead Breweries, undated (Box 39)
  - Toronto--Report on Montreal Creative Department, 1984 (Box 39)
  - Turkey, 1981-1982 (Box 39)
  - Turkey comes in from the cold (Economist), 1983 (Box 39)
  - Turkey--Manajans acquisition, 1983 (Box 39)
  - Turkey--Meeting with Eli Aciman, Manajans, 1984 (Box 39)
  - United Kingdom--JWT in the United Kingdom, undated (Box 39)
  - Vienna, 1984 (Box 39)
  - Vienna--Austrian market report, 1988 (Box 39)
  - Vienna--Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 39)
  - Vienna--Financial, 1984 (Box 39)
  - Vienna--JWT Vienna and the Austrian market, 1984 (Box 40)
  - Wally O'Brian, 1985-1986 (Box 40)
  - Zurich, 1984 (Box 40)
  - Zurich--Correspondence, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Zurich--Financial, 1984 (Box 40)
  - Zurich--Report on Switzerland, undated (Box 40)
- Financial, 1980-1990; 4
  - 1986 November reviews Europe region (Box 40)
  - Alfredo Campion, 1983-1985; 3 folders (Box 40)
  - Alfredo Campion--Financial, 1981-1985; 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Amsterdam--Internal audit report, 1984 (Box 41)
  - Amsterdam--Manager's monthly assessment, 1985 (Box 41)
  - Brussels--Manager's monthly assessment, 1985 (Box 41)
  - Cash management monitoring report, 1982 (Box 41)
  - Copenhagen--Final audit report, 1984 (Box 41)
  - Copenhagen--Manager's monthly assessment, 1985 (Box 41)
  - Dubai--Manager's monthly assessment, 1986-1987 (Box 41)
  - European region income statement, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
  - Finance manual, 1985 (Box 41)
  - Financial operating reviews Europe, 1981-1982; 3 folders (Box 41)
  - Financial statements, with auditor's reports, 1988-1989; 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Frankfurt--Investment program, 1982 (Box 42)
  - Germany--Expansion plan (English and German), 1982 (Box 42)
  - Group stock review, 1983 (Box 42)
  - JWT Securities Exchange Commission annual report, 1982 (Box 42)
  - Lansdowne Euro--Manager's monthly assessment, 1985-1987 (Box 42)
  - Lisbon--Manager's monthly assessment, 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 42)
  - MBRI--1983 financial report European offices (Box 42)
  - MRBI--Financial, 1984 (Box 42)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1983 (Box 42)
  - Price-Waterhouse audit, 1980 (Box 42)
  - Revised business expense policy, 1982 (Box 42)
  - Stock options, 1981-1983; 2 folders (Box 42)
  - Stockholm--Manager's monthly assessment, 1985 (Box 42)
  - TAAP (Thompson Achievement Awards Program) 1983 by office (Box 43)
  - Thompson company eight months operating results, 1983 (Box 43)
  - Thompson company monitoring report, 1983; 3 folders (Box 43)
  - Thompson company summary of financial results, 1982 (Box 43)
  - UK office reconciliation of DOP (Divisional Operating Profit) to profit before tax planning items, 1982-1983 (Box 43)
  - UK Holdings Limited, 1983 (Box 43)
  - Vienna--Manager's monthly assessment, 1985 (Box 43)
  - WPP Group PLC Drexel Burnham Lambert, 1987 (Box 43)
  - Zurich--Budget planning, 1990 (Box 43)
  - Zurich--Monthly Manager's meeting, 1985 (Box 43)
- Presentations and Speeches, 1978-1987 and undated; 5
  - 1982 presentations on media (Box 43)
  - Cronin board meeting presentation, 1985 (Box 43)
  - Cronin creative audit presentation to the Operations Committee, 1985 (Box 43)
  - Cronin notes for presentation to Mr. Caldwell (Ford Motor Company), 1983 (Box 43)
  - Cronin presentation--1982 European Manager's meeting, madrid--What business are we in? (Box 43)
  - Cronin presentation--Advertising in Europe, 1985 (Box 43)
  - Cronin presentation--Creative tour through Europe, European Manager's meeting, 1983 (Box 44)
  - Cronin presentation--European monthly Manager's meeting, 1981 (Box 44)
  - Cronin presentation--Europe 1984 (Box 44)
  - Cronin presentation--Future of the brand label; Food Processors Association 32nd annual convention, 1979 (Box 44)
  - Cronin presentation--How JWT Canada goes about getting new business (slides), undated (Box 44)
  - Cronin presentation--Institute of Canadian Advertising, 1981 (Box 44)
  - Cronin presentation--Stewardship report (slides), undated (Box 44)
  - Cronin script for tape, 1981 (Box 44)
  - Cronin speech--Advertising in Europe, 1985 (Box 44)
  - Cronin speech--Challenges we face together in the next 5 years; Central Canada Broadcaster Association, 1978 (Box 44)
  - Cronin speech--Future trends in advertising? International Marketing Management Conference, 1985 (Box 44)
  - Cronin speech--Growth from new business, 1985; 3 folders (Box 44)
  - Cronin speech--How to get new business, 1980 (Box 44)
  - Cronin speech--JWT Canada stewardship report, 1980 (Box 45)
  - Cronin speech--Outline of Tokyo staff presentation, 1987 (Box 45)
  - Cronin speech--Smarter spending of the shrinking advertising dollar: an advertising viewpoint of media trends (Association of Canadian Advertisers), 1977 (Box 45)
  - Cronin speeches given in Europe, 1980-1987; 4 folders (Box 45)
  - ECS (European Central Services) presentation, undated (Box 45)
  - James Webb Young Fund address by Walter Weir, 1987 (Box 45)
  - JWT: an approach to transnational communication (Roy Glah to Cronin; slides), 1983 (Box 45)
  - Maintaining the freedom to advertise; presentation to Advertising Association by Ogilvy and Mather, 1983 (Box 45)
  - MBRI--Asset and opportunity or liability and problem?, 1983 (Box 45)
  - Review of European advertising and some trends (George Black), 1986 (Box 45)
  - Speech--The natural economy of ideas (William Ross), 1980 (Box 45)
  - Speech--Ralph Cooper speech at Burger King International Convention, 1981 (Box 45)
  - Speeches at American Association of Advertising Agencies (Peter Scott, Brian Monahan), 1987 (Box 45)
- Printed Material, 1964-1990 and undated; 6
  - 1978 Middle East Report No. 1: the Gulf (Box 46)
  - 1978 Middle East Report No. 2: Iran (Geoffrey Dempsey) (Box 46)
  - 1978 Middle East Report No. 3: Egypt (Geoffrey Dempsey) (Box 46)
  - 1984-1985 annual reports JWT Group (Box 46)
  - 1985 National Creative Awards J. Walter USA (Box 46)
  - Account planning Europe "What is a brand", undated (Box 46)
  - Advertising Standards Board of Finance Limited publications, 1975-1980 (Box 46)
  - American Association of Advertising Agencies newsletters, 1982 (Box 46)
  - Associated Dairies Group report and accounts, 1985 (Box 46)
  - Bush House, Berlin, and Berkeley Square: George Butler remembers JWT 1925-1962, 1987 (Box 46)
  - Cable advertising in the eighties (Toby Syfret), 1983 (Box 46)
  - Child development summaries 4-11 years old, undated (Box 46)
  - Consumer has a mind as well as a stomach (Jeremy Bullmore), 1972 (Box 46)
  - Copenhagen Office--The Danish media structure, 1982 (Box 46)
  - EPCOT--JWT Through the looking glass, 1984 (Box 46)
  - EPCOT--Worldwide staff survey attitudes to JWT amongst executive staff, 1984 (Box 46)
  - European advertising review and forecast, 1984 (Box 46)
  - European satellite television from UK perspective, 1984 (Box 46)
  - Foreign investment in Turkey (Prime Ministry State Planning Organization, Foreign Investment Department), 1982 (Box 46)
  - I hear what you say (JWT communications guide by Tom Rayfield), 1987 (Box 46)
  - Institut Merieux promotional booklet on immunological applied research programs (French and English), 1985 (Box 46)
  - Introduction to advertising in the Gulf, 1978 (Box 46)
  - JWT Children's Panel--Summary of findings, 1993 (Box 46)
  - JWT corporate goal 1980 priorities and objectives (Jack Cronin), 1979 (Box 46)
  - JWT Directors' handbooks, 1987 (Box 46)
  - JWT London Accommodation, 1979 (Box 47)
  - JWT News, 1983 (Box 47)
  - JWT worldwide presentation to Mattel, 1983 (Box 47)
  - Leadman Labyrinth: A report prepared for Bill Ross by Robin Restall, 1980 (Box 47)
  - LWT (Holdings)--Programmes and Programme People, 1990 (Box 47)
  - LWT (Holdings)--Summary of LWT's application for the regional channel, 1991 (Box 47)
  - Madrid office--El mercado y nuestros anuncios (Spanish), 1984 (Box 47)
  - Media in France, 1982 (Box 47)
  - Media market in 1988 a forecast of media development over the next four years, 1984 (Box 47)
  - Middle East, 1978 (Box 47)
  - Middle East: JWT capability, 1978 (Box 47)
  - New business from multinationals: how do we get more of it, 1987 (Box 47)
  - Philips meeting Amsterdam, Philips annual report, 1986 (Box 47)
  - Proceedings from European Media Directors' conference at palma 1983 media update and video advertising, 1984 (Box 47)
  - Product marketed by Johnson worldwide companies, undated (Box 47)
  - Project Greece (Consultancy Group), undated (Box 47)
  - Project Turkey (Consultancy Group), 1974 (Box 47)
  - Readers of international media: a qualitative study in Europe (European Market Research Bureau), 1985 (Box 47)
  - Report on preliminary investigation of advertising agency scene in Turkey (Derrick Cawston), 1983 (Box 47)
  - Report on the acquisition of the Frank Small and Associates group in Southeast Asia/Australia, 1982 (Box 48)
  - Saatchi and Saatchi Company (Harvard Business School), 1987 (Box 48)
  - Should we down-weight for high readers-per-copy (Tom Corlett JWT ADMAP), 1982 (Box 48)
  - Sponsorship--JWT Europe examples, 1983 (Box 48)
  - Sponsorship--JWT UK examples, 1983 (Box 48)
  - Succeeding in competitive markets: a review by the Association of Market Survey Organizations, undated (Box 48)
  - The JWT T-Plan, 1964 (Box 48)
  - Treasures of Turkey (Istanbul Hilton magazine), 1982 (Box 48)
  - Trends in total advertising expenditure in 25 countries 1970-1979 (Box 48)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1983-1987 and undated; 7
  - Advertising in the pressure cooker--Jack Cronin, 1987 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-001)
  - Advertising: visual revolution or creative clutter, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-002)
  - Art Directors Club finalists japan 1986 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-003)
  - Characteristics of an advertising idea: some examples of demonstrations and metaphors, 1987 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-004)
  - Creative audit presentation (Summary), Operations Committee presentation Jack Cronin: September 1983 tape #1, 1985 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-005)
  - Creative audit selection (Complete) September 1985 tape #2 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-006)
  - Creative medium or creative message? Sao Paulo Brazil presentation, 1986 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-007)
  - Creative medium or creative message? revised 10/86, 1986 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-008)
  - Creative medium or creative message--Jack Cronin presentation to New York Office, December 4 1986 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-009)
  - Jack Cronin presentation to JWT Toronto (NTSC), 1983 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-010)
  - Jack Cronin JWT Group presentation 10th September 1985, New York (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-011)
  - Japan client presentation october, 1987, Jack Cronin (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-012)
  - Stephen King's Tool Kit workshop, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-013)
  - The Thompson Way of planning and creating adverting: an introduction to the principles, approaches and proprietary tools that characterize the way JWT plans and creates advertising. featuring Don Johnston, Jack Cronin, Marlene Hore, Jim Patterson, Allen Thomas and Stephen King, 1987 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11603-Umatic-014)